# Shuhei KAINUMA

### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Office Address | Universitetsvägen 10 A, plan 6 & 7, Stockholm, 114 18, Sweden

Email kainumelleo@gmail.com/shuhei.kainuma@ne.su.se

Website https://kainume.github.io

## **EDUCATION**

August 2021-	Ph.D. Student, Department of Economics, Stockholm University, Sweden	
April 2020- July 2021	Ph.D. Student, Graduate School of Economics, The University of Tokyo, Japan	
March 2020	M.A. in Economics, The University of Tokyo, Japan	
March 2018	Bachelor of Laws, <b>Osaka University</b> , Japan Affiliation: Department of International Public Policy, School of Law	
February 2016- January 2017	Occasional Studies: Humanities / Natural and Agricultural Sciences, University of the Free State, the Republic of South Africa	

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

Political Economics, Economic History, Development Economics, Applied Microeconometrics

### WORKING PAPERS

## RELEVANT POSITIONS

April 2021 – July 2021	Research Fellow (DC2), Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS)
February 2020 – August 2021	Research Assistant for Yoshito Takasaki (The University of Tokyo) Involved in the project "Ethnicity, disability, and vocational training in Rwanda"
June 2018 – March 2020	Research Assistant for Yukiko Saito (Waseda University and RIETI) Involved in the RIETI project "Dynamics of Inter-organizational Network and Firm Lifecycle"

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### Teaching Assistant, The University of Tokyo

Autumn 2019	Environmetal Economics, Graduate School of Public Policy
(Sep. – Jan.)	Instructor: Yoshito Takasaki (The University of Tokyo)
Spring 2019	International Development Policy and Evaluation, Graduate School of Public Policy
(Apr. – Jul.)	Instructor: Keitaro Aoyagi (Metrics Works Consultants Inc.)

<sup>&</sup>quot;Transition to Broader-Based Politics: The Role of Suffrage Extension in Early 20th Century Japan"

<sup>&</sup>quot;China's Impact on Regional Employment: Propagation through Supply Chain and Co-agglomeration Pattern" with Yukiko Saito (Previously circulated as RIETI Discussion Paper May 2020 20-E-054) *R&R at The World Economy* 

## Awards & Grants

August 2021 –	Graduate Scholarship for Degree Seeking Students, Japan Student Services Organization
April 2021 – July 2021	Grant-in-Aid for JSPS Fellows, Japan Society for the Promotion of Science
April 2019 –	<b>World-leading Innovative Graduate Study of Advanced Economics</b> , Graduate School of Economics, The University of Tokyo
February 2016 – November 2016	<b>Tobitate Young Ambassador Program</b> , Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan (Scholarship for Studying Abroad)

## **PRESENTATIONS**

### **Conference Presentations**

May 2020 | Japanese Economic Association 2020 Spring Meeting, Poster (Online)

### **Seminar Presentations**

June 2021	Faculty of Economics Seminars, Sophia University (Online)	
February 2021	TCJS Graduate Student Forum, UTokyo Center for Contemporary Japanese Studies, The	
	University of Tokyo (Online)	
July 2020	Workshop on the Economics of Human Resource Allocation, Osaka University (Online)	
January 2020	Empirical Micro Research Seminar, The University of Tokyo	
November 2019	Research Meeting on Economic History, The University of Tokyo	
July 2019	Research Meeting on Economic History, The University of Tokyo	

## Languages

English (fluent), Japanese (native)

## COMPUTER SKILLS

R, Stata, Python, MATLAB, QGIS, LATEX

## **BIOGRAPHY**

Birthday: October 1994 Birthplace: Nagano, Japan Citizenship: Japanese

## REFERENCES

Tetsuji Okazaki	Eric Weese	Chiaki Moriguchi
Faculty of Economics	Institute of Social Science	Institute of Economic Research
The University of Tokyo	The University of Tokyo	Hitotsubashi University